Contact

jotapedrocoutinho@hotmail.c

www.linkedin.com/in/joão-pedrode-souza-coutinho-b9440082 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Leadership
Career Development
Management

Languages

Portuguese (Native or Bilingual)
Spanish (Elementary)
German (Elementary)
English (Native or Bilingual)

João Pedro de Souza Coutinho

iOS Engineering Manager

Porto Alegre, Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil

Summary

I graduated from the Universidade Federal do Rio Grande do Sul with a Bachelor Degree in Computer Engineering.

My professional experience started in 2017 with web development (PHP + JavaScript and Java). Few months later I had the opportunity to join the mobile team to work with Android (Java) and iOS (Obj-C and Swift). Working with mobile development was always my dream, and after 1 year interchanging between stacks I decided to focus my career on iOS Development.

During this journey I've worked with many different clients from different areas such as Healthcare, Retailment, Shopping, Real Estate, Banking and Entertainment.

Experience

ArcTouch

1 year 8 months

iOS Engineering Manager July 2022 - Present (1 year 2 months) Brazil

Senior Software Engineer (iOS) January 2022 - July 2022 (7 months)

Porto Alegre, Rio Grande do Sul, Brasil

Agi

Mobile Software Engineer II February 2021 - December 2021 (11 months) Brazil

iOS Software Engineer

DX.CO Mid-level iOS Developer

February 2020 - February 2021 (1 year 1 month)

4all Tecnologia
Junior iOS Developer
June 2019 - February 2020 (9 months)
Porto Alegre, Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil

i9Access Tecnologia 2 years 1 month iOS App Developer November 2018 - May 2019 (7 months)

Android App Developer September 2017 - January 2019 (1 year 5 months) Porto Alegre

iOS App Developer January 2018 - April 2018 (4 months) Porto Alegre

Web Developer May 2017 - August 2017 (4 months) Porto Alegre

• PHP, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SQL.

Education

Universidade Federal do Rio Grande do Sul Bachelor of Engineering - BE, Computer Engineering · (2013 - 2019)